<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kim Schlesinger</title>
    <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kim Schlesinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 08:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kimschlesinger.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PATH, FHS and $PS1</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/path/</guid>
      <description>This is a companion blog post for a presentation I gave at the February 2020 DenverScript Meetup.
You can find the video recording and slide deck on my talks page.
The Path Variable   PATH is an enviornment variable.
  The variable is a colon-delimited string. The directory before each colon contains executable code and is invoked through a command, like pwd.
  To see the value, run echo $PATH from your command line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unnamed Privilege of Deep Work</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/deep-work-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/deep-work-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last blog post, I wrote about how I’ve developed some new work habits after reading Cal Newport’s book Deep Work. Applying the techniques have transformed how I approach challenging projects at work and in my spare time, and I’m reading, writing, and creating more than ever before.
Although Deep Work motivated me to change my habits, as I was reading the book, I noticed a quiet and persistent voice in my head telling me this style of work might not be for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/deep-work/</guid>
      <description>For the last fifteen weeks, I have been slowly tearing down and rebuilding my schedule and habits to support the style of work that Cal Newport describes in his 2016 book Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World. Although this is the first time I’ve read the book, I’ve been familiar with Newport and his ideas about learning and productivity for several years. When I was an Instructional Designer at a coding bootcamp, I read Newport’s Study Hacks blog and created student materials to help people use Active Recall while studying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Ways to Search Your Command Line History</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/search-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/search-cli/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you have to execute a complex command that you&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past. Instead of using the up-arrow key to scroll through your previous commands one at a time, here are two ways you can run a command without typing it again.
1. The history command  Type history and hit enter Find the number of the command you want to run again Use one of the following commands:  !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to Site Reliability Engineer</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/zero-to-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/zero-to-sre/</guid>
      <description>In the Spring of 2019, I spent a lot of time writing and giving a talk called Zero to SRE. Here are two blog posts from my company that cover the content of that talk:
 How To Invest In Junior Engineers Day One for Your Junior Engineer  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Commands for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/kubernetes-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/kubernetes-commands/</guid>
      <description>The Certified Kubernetes Application Developer Exam is a challenging, hands-on exam that requires you to configure and deploy applications and services in a real Kubernetes cluster. In this tutorial, I show how to run some basic kubectl commands that will get you started preparing for the CKAD.
In this video, I show how to do the following in a Kubernetes cluster:
 View and switch contexts Setup your preferred text editor  vim is the default, but can be set to nano   View pods in all namespaces View namespaces Create a namespace called practice Create a pod from yaml generated by the --dry-run flag Delete the pod Create the pod in the practice namespace Exec into the pod  To see the commands, checkout this github repo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Wiki</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/knowledge-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/knowledge-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Kim&amp;rsquo;s Knowledge Wiki
I am a software developer, and in order to keep my skills sharp, I spend a lot time during my evenings and weekends attending tech talks, reading technical books and watching video tutorials. I used to take notes using a pen or pencil in a notebook, or use multiple digital formats like Evernote, Google Docs, and the Mac notes app.
At the end of 2017, I started keeping my notes in a github wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deploy a Node.js API to Heroku</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/heroku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/heroku/</guid>
      <description>Heroku is the simplest way I know to deploy an application that requries read and write access to a database, like you would need for an API that can do CRUD operations (Create, Read, Update, Destroy).
By the end of this tutorial, you will see how to:
 Set up an application on Heroku Provision a postgres DB on Heroku Run knex commands to create the schema and seed a production database   Here&amp;rsquo;s a github gist with the commands: https://gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on How to Read More</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/read-more-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/read-more-2/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of July 2017, I set out to increase how much I read each month. It has been 28 days, and thus far I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen short of my goal, so I&amp;rsquo;m reflecting on my progress and making changes so I can keep reading.
Original Goal and Progress My goal was to read 700 minutes in 28 days. I ended up reading 550 minutes in 28 days.
Insights  25 minutes of uninterrupted reading is a stretch for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read More</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/read-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/read-more/</guid>
      <description>I have always admired people who are voracious readers, and as an adult, I have gone through several phases where I read whenever I can find a spare moment. Unfortunately, during the last six months, I have read very little aside from the newsfeed on my phone.
A few days ago, I realized I wanted to change this when I was listening to an interview of Karen Walker on the Women in Tech Show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn a Talk into an Active Learning Experience</title>
      <link>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/active-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 12:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kimschlesinger.com/post/active-learning/</guid>
      <description>Why? Attending a conference talk can expose you to new ideas or technologies, but you are passive during the presentation. In order to gain insight into new concepts, or be able to apply new skills, after the talk you will have to do the work of transforming your notes into an active learning experience. In this blog post, I explain how.
Step 1: Before the talk, set your intention. Prior to the talk, you should decide what you want to be able to do with the information you encounter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
